Guide to the Society of Rice University Women (SRUW) Records UA 153
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Society of Rice University Women (SRUW) Records
1968-2005
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Society of Rice University Women
UA 153
4.5 Linear Feet (9 boxes)
Records documenting the daily business of the Society of Rice University Women, including membership information, financial records and activity scrapbooks. Formats include membership lists, treasurer's reports, bank records, meeting minutes, event flyers, scrapbooks, photographs, and yearbooks.
Biographical / Historical
Established in the fall of 1968, the Society of Rice University Women promotes an effective and continuing dialogue between the university and its alumnae. Designed as a women's organization with which all could identify after graduation, SRUW also welcomes female friends of Rice to join and participate.
General meetings and seminars feature Rice professors and staff sharing their latest research and technology, as well as news of what is happening on campus.
Proceeds from seminars and dues benefit SRUW Scholarship Endowment Funds for female Rice students, the Fondren Library Woodson Research Center, and the Shepherd School of Music. SRUW is also a source of volunteers for campus activities.
Scope and Contents
Records documenting the daily business of the Society of Rice University Women, including membership information, financial records and activity scrapbooks. Formats include membership lists, treasurer's reports, bank records, meeting minutes, event flyers, scrapbooks, photographs, and yearbooks.
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Accruals
No future additions are expected for this material.
Provenance
The records were contributed by the membership of the Society of Rice University Women (SRUW).
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Women
Document Types
letters (correspondence); financial records; minutes (administrative records); programs (documents); directories
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University
- Series I: Early Records (programs, members, reports, minutes combined), 1968-1982; 90992
  - Programs, members, reports, minutes, 1968-1982; 90993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Members, 1994-2005; 90985
  - Members, 1994-1995; 90991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Members, 1995-1996; 90990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Members, 1996-1997; 90989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Members card file, 1997-1998; 90988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Members, 1999-2001; 90987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Obituaries, 2001-2005; 90986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series III: Board members, 1986-1999; 90982
  - Board members, 1986-1989, 1996-1997, 1998-1999; 90984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Board job descriptions, post 1996; 90983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Events information, 1974-2005; 90980
  - Events information, 1974-2005; 90981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series V: Correspondence, 1991-2000; 90977
  - General correspondence, 1998-2001; 90979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Gift correspondence and receipts, Rice University, 1991-2000; 90978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Series VI: Minutes, 1982-2001; 90971
  - Board minutes, 1982-1989; 90976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - General minutes, 1982-1989; 90975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - General minutes, September 13, 1999; 90974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - General minutes, April 10, 2000; 90973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, June 11, 2001; 90972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series VII: Bylaws, n. d.; 90969
  - Bylaws, n. d.; 90970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series VIII: Financial records, 1988-2001; 90950
  - Cash book, 1988-1990; 90968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Financial statements, 1990-1993; 90967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bills paid, 1992-1993; 90966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Treasurer's records, 1992-1994; 90965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Treasurer's records, 1994-1995; 90964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bank statements, 1995-1996; 90963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Treasurer's records, 1996; 90962 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bills paid, 1995-1997; 90961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Texas Sales Tax permits and records, 1997-1999; 90960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bank statements, 1997-1998; 90959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bank statements, 1998-1999; 90958 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Treasurer's records, 1998; 90957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bank deposits (1of 2), 1998-1999; 90956 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bank deposits (2 of 2), 1998-1999; 90955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Checks, 1999-2000; 90954 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Bank deposits, 1999-2000; 90953 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Treasury records, 2000; 90952 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Bank statements, 2000-2001; 90951 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Series IX: Yearbooks, 1972-2005; 90944
  - Yearbooks, 1972-1980; 90949 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Yearbooks, 1980-1990; 90948 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Yearbooks, 1990s; 90947 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Yearbooks, 1999-2000; 90946 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Yearbooks, 2001-2005; 90945 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Series X: Activity scrapbooks and photographs, 1970-2005; 90930
  - Activity scrapbooks, 1970-1978; 90943 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Activity scrapbooks, 1979-1981; 90942 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Activity scrapbooks, 1982-1986; 90941 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Activity scrapbooks, 1987-1990; 90940 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Activity scrapbooks, 1990-1992; 90939 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Activity scrapbooks, 1992-1993; 90938 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Activity scrapbooks, 1993-1994; 90937 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Activity scrapbooks, 1995-1998; 90936 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Activity scrapbooks, 1998-1999; 90935 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, 2000; 90934 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 2001-2002; 90933 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 2005; 90932 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, n. d.; 90931 (Box 9, Folder 6)